Welcome to the Archon beta launch party
live stream recap/condensed
version. We had a super exciting live
stream yesterday that ended up going
three hours long. So I wanted to create
a shorter version for you so you can
still get basically all the value that I
gave yesterday but in a third of the
time. So I cut out a lot of things like
the Q&A and waiting for Claude Code to
finish different parts of our
development flow. But if you really do
want to be a part of the live stream
definitely check out the full thing.
I'll have that linked in the
description. And also be sure to check
out the video that I'll link to right
here where I introduce Archon on my
channel for the first time. And the
purpose of this live stream was twofold.
First of all, I wanted to give you a
live demonstration of using Archon to
give you a deeper understanding of its
purpose and how you can leverage it. And
then second of all, I wanted to show you
that archon works really, really well
with existing strategies for context
engineering that you might be using like
cloud flow, the BMAD method, spectrum of
development, the PRP framework, all
these different strategies. And I prove
that because the focus of this live
stream is using Archon with the BMAD
method, which also has been highly
requested on my channel recently. So,
I'm super excited to bring that to you.
So, that's everything that we've got
here for the condensed version of this
live stream that you're about to watch.
With that, let's get right into it.
Welcome everyone to the Archon beta
launch party live stream. I've been
looking forward to this all week, all
month, all summer because we've been
working our butts off on Archon for so
long and now we have the beta launch and
I cannot wait for it. So yeah, with that
I want to really quickly talk about the
plan for the stream today and just like
the general structure for it and then
I'll share my screen and we'll just dive
right into things. So, first of all,
this is going to be a pretty casual
stream. I'm going to be kind of like
leveraging Archon as you would as a new
user just getting used to the platform,
figuring out how you want to integrate
it in your own AI development workflow.
And uh maybe I can actually go ahead and
share my screen. Okay, so what we're
going to be doing today is you guys
hopefully saw the launch the beta launch
video for Archon on Wednesday. Now, I
want to dive deeper into using Archon.
We're going to be building something
from scratch. I'll talk about how we can
use Archon in existing code bases as
well, but I want to start by showing you
guys kind of talking about what Archon
is all about. Uh, just to sort of recap
some of the things I talked about in the
the launch video on Wednesday. Then I'll
I'll quickly show like how you can get
it set up. We'll poke around the user
interface a little bit. I'll show like
how you connect it to your AI coding
assistant with MCP. Then we'll get into
using it. And to kind of more simulate
what it'd be like for you guys to play
around with it for the first time, I'm
going to be using Archon in a
development workflow that I'm not very
familiar with myself. So, we're going to
be doing some freestyling in this
stream. It's going to be fun. And so the
development workflow that we are going
to be covering in this stream is the
BMAD method which by the way it is
insane how many comments I get from you
guys in my videos and in the Dynamis
community asking for me to cover BMAD.
So there's a lot of love for this. It is
a really really cool framework. Um just
one of the methods that we have for
context engineering. So I cover the PRP
framework a lot on my channel. Um, I've
talked about the spectriven development
that we have in AI idees like Curo. BMAD
is another method for context
engineering. And so, we're going to be
integrating BMAD with Archon in this
stream. And I've done a little bit of
prep just to make sure I understand how
BMAD works overall, but I haven't used
it ever to build a project end to end.
And so, like I said, very much
freestyling. I'm going to be playing
around with how I can integrate Archon
with BMAD with you guys live so that you
get a sense of if you're integrating
Archon into your development workflow.
What does it look like to just poke
around and experiment with prompting and
using the Archon MCP to really build it
into what you're doing already? Like
everyone here has an existing process or
at least you're starting to get yourself
introduced to using coding assistance.
And so I want to make it really easy to
see how Archon can fit in no matter what
you already are doing for your AI
development workflow. So that's what
we're going to be doing and it's going
to be fun. So the first thing that I
want to talk about before we get into
this is just you know what Archon is
about. And so I'll I'll dive into that
in a second. And I guess the the last
thing that I want to say here before we
dive into things is
um there might be a lot of like let's
just dive into things and and get things
to work. It's going to be kind of
scrappy. It's going to be fun, but I
don't know for sure if we're going to
have something working end to end by the
end of this live stream because more of
the point is diving into how we can
experiment with integrating Archon into
our workflow versus like let's fully
build something end to end. Like I don't
have the live stream structured in that
way and I'm doing that intentionally. um
for the reasons that I've already been
talking about. So I don't I don't want
to repeat myself here. The the one thing
I'll say though is if you're interested
in seeing my full development workflow
in a much more structured way talking
about context engineering and archon and
how I use it in my workflow. Something
really exciting that I've got going on
um in the Dynamis community and let me
I'll actually uh bring this over from my
other monitor here. I'm hosting a
half-day workshop, a 4hour workshop.
It's going to be the end of this month,
Wednesday, August 27th. And this is
where I'm going to dive into a much more
structured approach. So, it's going to
be a lot different from this live
stream. Like, this live stream is going
to be more casual. We're just building
things, freestyling together. I'm going
to be answering a lot of your guys'
questions in the chat throughout as
well. But, this workshop is going to be
a lot more structured. Like, I'll dive
into my full AI development workflow.
We're going to build something from
scratch using PRPs and archon. A lot of
the things that I've been covering on my
channel is going to be in this very
comprehensive workshop. So, if you're
interested in this, like my goal is to
make it so that this this workshop alone
is worth the investment of Dynamist. And
so, uh, yeah, I just wanted to mention
that really quickly because it's it's
very much like related to like here's
what you'd want to do if you like what
we're diving into in this live stream
and you want something that's a lot more
structured. So definitely check out
Dynamus also because the prices will for
Dynamis are going to increase after um
this weekend. So this is like the
special Archon beta launch weekend and
then prices are going to go up after. So
I just wanted to mention that quickly. U
but for our workshop right now, we're
just going to have a really good time.
And so yeah, let's go over to the Archon
repo here. It is the operating system
for AI coding. And so what that means is
it's the command center. So for us, it's
a sleek user interface. Like if I go to
the project management for example,
we've got a sleek user interface to
manage all of our tasks. We've got a
place to manage the knowledge that we
want to give our coding assistants. So I
can perform rag to like actually search
through the pyantic AI documentation or
the cloud code documentation. So it's a
UI for us to manage everything. And then
for the coding assistant, it's an MCP
server. So it's kind of like leveraging
what's native to humans and what's
native to coding assistants. So we all
can work on the same set of context as
we are context engineering. That's the
beauty of it. And it's possible to
connect it to any AI coding assistant
that supports MCP. And so we have
instructions if I go to like the MCP
server tab. And I'll talk about how you
can get this all running in a second by
the way. Uh but like we have a tab for
all the popular coding assistants and um
really just to keep the UI concise. We
didn't include like 20 different coding
assistants, but you can connect this to
every single coding assistant basically.
So we have instructions for popular ones
like Klein and Claude Code like we'll be
using today. I'll actually copy this
command right here. So this is the
command that you run when you have
Claude installed to hook in the Archon
MCP server. And um actually maybe I'll
actually just go ahead and do that right
now. So, I've got my terminal open.
We're going to be living and breathing
in this terminal today as we do our
demo. And so, to add the archon mcp
after I have it up and running, I just
have to run this command. Like, it's
that easy. And I already have it
running, which is why I get this message
right here. But if I do a cloud MCP
list, then it'll check and even validate
the connection to Archon. So, that's how
easy it is to get it connected once you
have the UI up and running. And I I
cover instructions for like how to set
up everything in the video that I put
out on Wednesday. But really, if you go
to this link, so you can just go to the
Archon GitHub repository. Also, if you
just go to the URL archon.y,
this will take you to the GitHub
repository as well. So, I have a a URL
that just like redirects you right to
the to the GitHub repo. So, it's really
easy for you guys to access it. Um, so
yeah, just archon.diy.
And then in the read me here, I have
your quick start instructions. So, super
super easy to get started. There are a
couple of things that people have been
tripping up on that I want to address
really quickly. Uh because honestly,
like if you guys want to follow along in
this live stream as I start using
Archon, I'd welcome it. Um and so, yeah,
prerex, you just need to have Docker
Desktop. Uh you need a Superbase
account. You can the free tier works
like you don't have to pay anything to
use Archon. Um or you can even use local
Superbase. So like if you're following
along with my all my local AI stuff and
you have the local AI package up and
running, you can use that superbase. Um
and then also you just need your API key
for OpenAI. We also support Gemini and
Olama. So Olama is kind of more
experimental right now. It's in the
works. Um but we are we have actually an
active effort on that with a PR coming
into Archon soon as well. And that's
kind of the other big preface I want to
give for Archon is like when I say that
it's in beta like there there are things
that are like not working 100% at this
point and there are more experimental
parts of the platform that um we have
like things that are saying coming soon
or it just does like it needs to be
tidied up. We're working on that. Like
I'm I'm putting in a lot of my effort a
majority of my effort into Archon and
everything related to context
engineering that I have like kind of
playing into Archon. So yeah, these are
the prerexs and then you just have to
clone the repo and then set up your
environment variables and really it's
just you have to get your superbase URL
and service ro key. And maybe I could
actually show that really quick as well.
I feel like that'd be useful just for
the people that have been tripping up.
One thing that I've been seeing a lot is
um people are using their anonymous key
in Superbase instead of their service
roll one. And so I'm just going to bring
over my Superbase here and show you what
I'm talking about. So, I have a just
like a basic $10 a month micro instance
set up for a lot of the testing I've
been doing with Archon. You just go to
your project settings in Superbase. And
when you go to the API key section, you
just reveal and copy the service role
key. So, that's the key that you put
into the environment variables for
archon. And then for the data API, you
get your URL here.
And then you can do a similar thing for
uh self-hosted superbase. You just get
your values from the environment
variables. So, not to dive too much into
the setup right now just because I
covered that in the video on Wednesday
already, but I wanted to at least call
that out because a couple of uh issues
have been created around that. Um, so
yeah, and then once you have your
environment variable set up, you can set
up your database. And so within the
migrations folder, I've got a single
script that you can run. You can copy
this script, go into your Superbase SQL
editor, and you can create a new
snippet, and then you just paste this in
and run it. So, this is going to create
all of the archon tables for managing
your knowledge and your tasks and your
documents. Uh, very, very easy setup.
And then I'll go back to the readme
here. Um, because then the last thing is
to build spin up the containers. So, you
just run this docker compose command. We
got docker as one of our pre-wax for
this. And so, you run that and it'll
spin up all the containers. And then you
have everything running for archon. And
so what that'll look like in your Docker
desktop is you'll have four containers
running under the archon umbrella. We've
got our agents, which this is a feature
that is more coming soon. But then we
have our MCP server, the user interface
that we've already been looking at a
bit, and then we have our server that
has all of our API endpoints so that our
UI can interact with everything that the
MCP server can for our coding assistant.
So that's what the setup looks like. And
then if you go to local host port 3737,
that'll take you through an onboarding
flow where we have you set your OpenAI
API key um or you can just skip past
that and then go and set your uh Google
API key. So we support Gemini as well.
And then Olama, like I said, is
experimental coming soon. So a lot of
things that we're working on that are
coming soon. Um it's like things like
Olama. So yeah. Uh, and then once you're
in Archon and you have everything set
up, this is where the fun begins because
this is where we can start to scrape
knowledge and get our global rule set up
for Archon. This is where the fun
begins. And so
yeah, um, to start, I think now is a
good time. I'm I'm going to kind of like
treat this as if I'm using Archon from
scratch. So, I have some things that are
crawled already that I'm going to be
using in the the demo today, but I'm
going to act like I don't have that. And
so, I'm going to start from scratch,
talk about like what we're going to be
building, and I put a lot of thought
into just having like a really cool use
case for you guys. And then, we'll get
into the BMAD method. We'll actually
start more with BMAD and then start
seeing how Archon can play into it
because I want to show you guys how your
existing strategies work with Archon.
So, what we're going to be building
today is going to be something kind of
like this tool. So, if you guys haven't
heard of Claude Code UI, and there's a
lot of tools that are like it, it's
basically a user interface. So, like in
mobile and on the web, we can manage
different Claude Code instances. And so,
I'll open this image in a new tab so you
guys can see kind of like like what what
I envision creating. And again, we might
not like have an end result that looks
like this by the end of this stream
because I want to focus so much on like
answering your guys's questions, talking
about Archon, and integrating with BMAD,
but we might get something kind of like
we'll see. Well, this is kind of what
I'm envisioning here where we have a
user interface. We'll build a website
with Nex.js JS where we have just like
an easier way to manage the our cloud
code instances and we'll use the cloud
code SDK that they offer so that we can
build our own application that is
invoking cloud code and we can manage um
the different instances at the same
time. We can see like a log of the
terminals that we have open and all the
work that they're doing which is also
going to be a cool way to manage sub
agents by the way within cloud codes.
you can have them all running at the
same time and managing them separately
and like having that integrated with
Archon as well. So like this is kind of
just to give you guys like a rough idea
of what I'm envisioning here, what we're
going to create together. Um just to
give you a demo of BMAD plus Archon and
yeah, Cloud Code UI is not a tool that
I've actually tried myself. I've used
other similar ones, but I just found
this one recently and I thought that
this was like a they just had nice
screenshots showing what it looks like.
So, I thought it'd be a nice way to give
you guys a visual of what I'm hoping to
create because obviously I can't give
you guys a demo of something like I do
in my YouTube videos because in my
YouTube videos, I'll fully build it out
first, then I'll record basically like
recreating it. So, that way I can like
give you guys a demo up front and then
create basically a replica so you see
the full process. So, that's what it
looks like in something a lot more
structured like a YouTube video or like
that workshop that I have in Dynamus
coming up here. Um, but then for this
live stream, we're just freestyling. So,
that's what I want to create. So, all
right. Now, we can dive into BMAD. And,
uh, by the way, once we start using
BMAD, that's when we'll have more
natural breaks for me to take a look at
the chat here. So, I have the chat on my
left monitor. I see that it's going
crazy. I appreciate all you guys being
here and commenting. So, I'll definitely
be diving into uh some of your guys's
questions once uh we got some things
running in Cloud Code. So, let's start
with a little intro to BMAD and then
once we start looking into how we use
it, that's when we'll really start to
see Archon play into it in a way where
like I think you guys will be able to
use your imagination to see how Archon
can fit into any AI development
workflow. So BMAD it is the foundation
of agentic agiled driven development and
um yeah actually I think 125% is a good
zoom here. So I'll stay at this level of
zoom. Um so there's kind of two main
workflows that we have with BMAD.
Essentially what BMAD gives us is a
bunch of different sub aents that are
experts at different parts of our
development workflow. So like in the
agentic planning workflow, we have our
analyst, we have our project manager, we
have our architect, and then when we go
into development, we have our scrum
master agent that's kind of guiding all
these different development agents to
knock out the different stories like the
different tasks that we have for
developing our project. And there are
some diagrams that we have in the user
guide here um that walk us through what
this workflow looks like. And yeah, so
the the BMAD method in general, it's
like I said, it's a strategy for context
engineering and it gets pretty in-depth.
Like these workflow diagrams that like
these mermaid diagrams, they look kind
of intimidating. Like there's a lot that
goes into this here. So um yeah, by the
way, like this first one is the planning
workflow. And we're going to walk
through this and I'll show you how to
integrate Archon with this. It's not as
complex as it looks. This is the
planning workflow. Then once we get into
development, we have this second
workflow, which I might go through this
one or I might actually switch to PRP.
Um, we'll see. Like I said, we're
freestyling here. So, two different
workflows that we have for the BMAD
method. And the guy that created the
BMAD method, he he's a genius. Like,
he's very, very smart. And he's actually
got a YouTube channel where he started
covering BMAD. I went through his entire
1 hour and 15 minute master class that
he had on YouTube. By the way, if you
just search the BMAT method, you'll find
him. Um, but yeah, he's done so much
research into project management and
best practices for architecting and
different like mental models that we can
apply to planning projects. And he's
done a ton of research into best
practices for prompting at different
stages of our AI development workflow.
And he talks a lot about that in his
master class as well. And so I I just
think this is a great use case. So like
apply BMAD with archon. And the other
thing that he talks about is the whole
idea of um green field versus brownfield
projects. So a green field project, you
can think of it like fresh green
pastures. This is a new project that
you're starting from scratch. And then
brownfield is when you're working in an
existing codebase. And the BMAD method
has different workflows depending on if
you're working on an existing codebase
or not. And I know that that's something
that um a lot of you guys like in
comments in my videos and in the Dynamis
community have said like I want to see
more of like let's use AI coding on an
existing project versus something that
is green field. And so generally I focus
on green field new projects just because
it's a lot easier to show how I apply
different strategies. And it's going to
be the same in this live stream. on
creating something from scratch because
going through the full planning
workflow, it's much easier to integrate
Archon and show the different parts of
Archon when we're doing a lot more of
that like initial research and task
management. Um, where we're it's going
to be a lot more sparse if we're just
like adding new features on an existing
codebase. There's going to be less tasks
overall. There's going to be less
research that we have to perform with
Archon and like all the knowledge that
we have for Rag because it's going to be
more looking at the existing codebase
versus looking at documentation. You see
what I'm saying? Like brownfield
projects, it's more let's reference the
existing codebase to figure out the
patterns that we need to develop. With a
new project, it's let's look at the
documentation for pideanti for example
to figure out the patterns for
developing agents that are that's
recommended for this library. So that's
why we're going with green field here.
The sponsor of this live stream recap is
Sneak and they're bringing us a free
webinar that you don't want to miss. If
you're using AI coding assistance, if
you're vibe coding or even using a more
structured approach to using AI coders
like we're doing with Archon and PRPs,
there are still security concerns that
go beyond traditional code review.
That's why Sneak is hosting this free
webinar Thursday, August 28th at 11:00
a.m. Eastern time. Securing Vibe Coding,
addressing the security challenges of AI
generated code. The focus is going to be
specific to the unique risks that we
have with these AIdriven development
workflows. How it differs from typical
security concerns. This is the kind of
thing that we have to be focusing on.
Sonia, a staff developer advocate at
Sneak, is going to be introducing us to
how vibe coding is changing the
landscape of development, what these new
security concerns are with AI powered
coding, and how we can implement
strategies today to reduce these risks
and protect our AI powered development
life cycle. If you're in security,
DevOps, or just using AI coding
assistance at all, this is the webinar
for you to give you the frameworks you
need to work with AI coding assistants
securely. Plus, if you are an ISC2
member, you get one CPE credit just for
attending this webinar. So, go ahead and
register with the link that I have in
the description. Again, it's Thursday,
August 28th at 11:00 a.m. Eastern. I'm
going to be there myself, so I will see
you there. So, let's let's go ahead and
start actually. So, going back to BMAD
here,
I'm going to copy the command to get
started. And so, it's super super easy
to get BMAD started in any project. Um,
all you have to do, and I mean I've
already run this, and so I'll probably
just do it on a new folder, show you
guys what it looks like, and then I'll
go back to my current folder where I
already have BMAD set up. I think
that'll be the best way to do it. So,
let me go and get things set up in a new
folder here. Okay. All right. So, I take
that command from the repo. It's just
npx bad method install. Super easy. And
it's going to install the following
packages. That is good. All right. BMAD
method. And then the first thing you
want to do is enter the full path to
your project because essentially what
BMAD will do is just it's going to
install a bunch of configuration and sub
aents like a lot of different markdown
files to get us set up with BMAD in our
codebase. So this can be an existing
codebase that you install BMAD into or
in our case it can just be a brand new
folder. And so I'm going to pass in a
path here. I'll call it uh BMAD
example.
There we go. And then I'm going to
install the full system here. And uh
will the PRD product requirement
document be sharded into multiple files?
Yes. Is the default. Just go with this.
PRDS. By the way, guys, this is like the
document that has like a very fully
written out spec of what you want to
create. So when we plan our initial
implementation, we put that in a PRD
that we'll then use to break into tasks
and start implementing. And we'll see
that in action as well. So I'm going to
say yes. Will the architecture
documentation be sharded into multiple
files? Sharded just means split up to
make things more concise, by the way. So
yeah, now we get to pick the IDE that we
want to configure because based on the
coding assistant, there are different
ways that we need to set up our global
rules and set up our sub aents, things
like that. So I'm going to pick cloud
code. So select with spacebar and then
confirm with enter. And you can install
this in multiple ones, by the way, but
uh I'm just going to go ahead and put
this in cloud code. So there we go.
Enter to confirm. Uh pre-built web
bundles. I don't really care about that.
So I'll just select the default. And
then it says the directory does not
exist. Would you like to create the
directory and continue? I will say yes.
There we go. All right. Boom. Super
super quick. So there we go. We have
everything created. So it created some
agents for us. So we have these
different commands that we can use to
invoke these sub aents. So like for
example when we are first starting our
project and we'll see this in a sec when
we want to start planning things we'll
call into the analyst agent that BMAD
gives us and we'll use the an the
analyst will actually leverage archon to
crawl through the documentation for
cloud code in next.js JS to help us
create some kind of more like initial
pseudo code like that first layer of
like okay let's think about generally
how we want to structure the codebase
and we'll actually use archon with the
analyst to do that and then the analyst
is going to output a brief like a
project brief that we're going to store
as a document in a new project in
archon. So that's kind of a little
teaser for what we're about to do here.
Um, but yeah, whenever we do this and we
create a new setup with BMAD, I'll open
my VS Code and I'll show you really
quickly what this looks like in general.
So, that's going to create this uh BMAD
core folder. So, this this works on an
existing project as well. It's not going
to like overwrite anything in your
codebase. It creates a new folder where
we have our different agent teams, our
agents. We got the core user guide here.
These are all the files that are going
to be referenced by our agents as we
call upon them in our development
workflow. And so like here's the
markdown file for the analyst agent for
example.
And so yeah basically like we have each
agent starts with an activation notice.
So it's like when we call upon the
analyst agent here's what you got to do
and then here are the steps that you
have to follow to act as the analyst
agent. So when we tell claude code or
cursor or winds surf whatever to act as
this agent it reads this file and then
basically uses these instructions to
change its persona. That's how we're
doing. So it's not the BMAD doesn't
actually use like the slash agent
feature in cloud code. And the reason
for that is it's more of like a general
implementation so that you can use
basically sub aents as prompts in any
coding assistant even the ones that
don't have sub aents built into it. And
so yeah, sub aents, if you guys didn't
know, sub aents, even in cloud code,
it's really just prompts. Like you have
some file that you tell cloud code to
look at and you say read the
instructions here to act as this
persona. That's all we're doing here.
And so we're telling it that like you
your name is Mary, you're a business
analyst, uh here is your role and your
style, here are your core principles,
and then here are the different commands
that a user can invoke. like we have our
help command, we have our command to
create our project brief, which is one
of the first things we're going to do.
So that's essentially how BMAD works is
we have all these different agents that
are fit together in this workflow that I
was showing you guys in the mermaid
diagram earlier, which was um if I pull
that up quick, I'll just reference that
for you guys again.
Um that is this diagram here. So the
analyst is at the beginning here. And so
we can go ahead and invoke this. And so
let's let's just dive right in. So I'm
going to clear and then I'm going to
enter in a clot. And by the way, cloud
MCP list, remember we've got Archon
connected already. I showed you guys how
to do that. Maybe I didn't kind of do it
in the right order. Like I showed you
how to connect Archon, then I went
through like setting it up, but yeah. So
we we we connected it with um this
command right here, assuming we have
everything up and running. The MCP for
Archon is on port 8051 by default. And
you can configure that as well if you
want. So yeah, we'll jump into a cloud
session here and let's get right into
it. And so I've I came with a little bit
of prep.
Um, so I know some of the commands that
I want to run here. So I have that
referenced on my other monitor here just
to try to make this smooth. Um, though
we are mostly freestyling like I haven't
done that much. And so the first thing
that we want to do is if you just do
slanalyst and then you press tab, we're
going to start Mary as our analyst and
it's going to help us create our brief
for the project that we want to create.
So there we go. Slanalyst. Hello, I'm
Mary, your business analyst. Specialize
in blah blah blah. And then type help to
see my available commands. So, we can do
star help. And then Mary is going to be
prompted to give us the commands that
she has everything that we had in the um
that markdown file that I showed you.
And while she outputs that, the other
thing I want to show you guys, if I go
back to Archon here,
we have the global rules that we want to
create for Archon. So, in the settings,
and you're going to want to do this
whenever you use archon, we have the IDE
global rules. And so, based on if you're
using cloud code or not, really, there's
just like special instructions for cloud
code that we have, and then the rest of
your coding assistants can use the same
rules here. You can just copy the cloud
code rules and then you can either
create a new cloudMD and paste these in
along with the typical global rules that
you use or if it's an existing project
where you already have global rules then
you'll just paste in the instructions
for archon along with everything else
that you already have. So whether it's
your claw.md or your cursor rules or
your winds surf rules this is just part
like this is the part of your global
rules now for archon. So you can add
this in with any of your other existing
global rules. So I just wanted to call
that out really quickly because I have
that set up in this repository already
or this folder already. Otherwise, I
literally just have my global rules and
then everything for BMAD and then some
stuff for PRP that we'll get into
towards the end here. So that's what I
have set up right now. So going back to
the terminal here, here are the commands
that we have for the business analyst.
And so uh we can create a project brief.
we can go into YOLO mode, which I I saw
someone in the chat was asking about
YOLO mode. Um, yolo mode is instead of
like it working alongside you more to
plan your project, implement your
project, it it operates more
autonomously. So, if you want to just
trust it more with the implementation,
that's what yolo mode means. We're going
to do some of that here because I want
to be pretty concise in going through
the BMAD method here. But the first
thing that I want to do is I want to
brainstorm. So I'm going to use the
brainstorm command. So you do like uh
star brainstorm. So the star is just the
way to like signal that we were invoking
a command here. That's just the
convention for BMAD. We do star
brainstorm and then we just send in a
prompt for what we want it to research.
And so what I want to do, I have this
pre-selected just so you guys don't have
to see me type it out here. I want to
create a nex.js front end where I can
spin off and manage different cloud code
instances through the cloud code SDK.
And I'm speaking to the specific pieces
of technology cloud code and next.js
that I have the documentation for in
archon. And so we'll see in a little bit
how I'm actually going to ask Mary to
reference the documentation through
archon so that we can get a better
planning. Basically just get a better
brief outputed. So there we go. So now
there's quite a few different things
that we can do after the brainstorming
just based on those same commands that
we saw when I did the help command
earlier.
And so what I want to do is I want to do
a uh I want to create a project brief.
So
I'm going to do create project brief.
That's just one of the commands that we
have for the analyst. I can just say
two. I want to do command number two. So
instead of yeah like it it's I'm just
going to like go through the flow that
it's walking me through here and just
kind of trust it more. So I'm going to
say two. I want to create a detailed
project brief for this concept. And the
analyst here is prompted to guide me
through it so that I can really be a
part of creating the brief. It's not
just going to go and off and do it all
itself. And so in a second here, we'll
see it maybe ask a couple of follow-up
questions for us.
Um, so let's see.
All right, got some output here. So it's
starting to it's got the executive
summary here. So it's starting to do
some planning. We'll see if it I mean
it's kind of it's not always the same
how the analyst works. Like sometimes
we'll ask people more follow questions,
sometimes it won't. I mean the BMAD
method is not always going to like
perform the same because LLMs are just
unreliable. They don't always do the
exact same thing. Like they won't always
ask me the same follow-up questions. So
I'll just kind of let it rip here. We
got success metrics and KPIs.
We've got a timeline and milestones. So
Mary is very much acting like a project
manager here, outlining really important
things like what's the timeline for our
project. I mean, this isn't actually
going to take 24 weeks. This is this is
hilarious. It's not going to be 24
weeks. I promise guys, you're not stuck
in this live stream for 24 weeks. Uh but
yeah, we got key milestones, risk
assessment, resource requirements,
which I mean this isn't really accurate
to what we're doing here. I I guess
maybe if we create like sub agents for
each of these things, I suppose. Um, I'm
about to spend $200,000 on development.
That's kind of funny. So may maybe the
prompting for the business analyst could
be a bit more accurate to like actually
integrating this in development
workflow, not with like real people that
we have to pay. But you guys get the
idea in general. Like it's pretty cool
how we have this entire project brief.
And so the next thing that I want to do
with this brief is I actually want to
refine it and then store it as a
document in Archon. So, we'll start to
see more how archon is integrated with
uh the BMAD method here. So, okay, I'm
going back to my instructions here. I'm
trying to remember exactly what I want
to do next with this.
Um,
yeah, let's see. So, I'm going to I'm
actually going to run the the help
command again because I want to remember
what commands I have. Um,
and then also there are some follow-up
questions that we've got here. create
user stories, develop competitive
analysis, which I'm not really
interested in doing that right now.
Generate technical implementations.
Um, what else could I do?
Um, and actually, does it did the
project brief get created? No, it didn't
get created yet. Okay. So, I'm going to
let's just say this. I'm going to say
use archon to
uh search how to leverage the cloud code
SDK.
and then
add technical implementation
ideas to the project brief and save that
brief in a new project I want you to
create in Archon. Okay, so here we go.
This is where we really start to see the
integration here. So, we're going to
have Mary instead of just going through
the typical flow that you do with the
BMAD method where you store all your
documents in your source control like
just in your your project folder, we're
going to actually have her use archon.
So, she's going to do some research on
how to leverage the cloud code SDK so
that she can help me generate a more
technical implementation plan and
actually do it based on the cloud code
documentation instead of just like
simple research or hallucinating
something random. It's going to use
archon. That's going to help a lot. And
then we'll store the brief in Archon as
well. And we'll do that in a brand new
project that we create. So going back to
Archon here within a single project,
we've got the tasks tab and then we have
the docs tab. So we'll see Mary create a
new project in Archon. In a second here,
this will pop up and then there'll be a
project brief as well.
So first of all, before she does that,
she's going to search through our
documentation. So everything that we
crawled like I showed you crawling the
cloud code um the cloud code
documentation in real time that is what
we're searching through using the archon
mcp. So we're performing rag queries and
then we're also searching through the
code examples that you saw being
generated as well. So I'm going to do if
I do controlr and cloud code we can zoom
into the output of our different rag
searches. So like when we searched for
code examples, we were looking for
TypeScript implementations
and um let's see what we got here.
Trying to like I mean there's just a lot
of information here. I mean it's okay
that we don't have to like understand
all this in detail but the coding
assistant definitely needs to. So let's
go up to uh the first chunk that we
retrieved.
So uh let's see.
It's kind of hard to like
Okay, so here we go. But we got some
some implementations with the cloud SDK.
So it's pulling things from the cloud
SDK which is good. Um and then we got
some things for the TypeScript SDK. So
that's what we actually care about using
here. Um so this is good. We're getting
some of the code examples. And I'll do
control R to go out of this. We don't
need to like dive into that forever
here. Uh but the important thing is if I
go back into Archon, I didn't even have
to refresh my page because we have
websockets. So there's real time updates
with Archon through the MCP and the UI.
We have our cloud code instance manager
Nex.js control center project. So there
we go. We got a a blank slate here. So
we got no tasks at this point, no docs,
but we're about to create the brief. And
so we'll see that here. Now we'll add
the enhanced project brief with
technical implementation to the newly
created project. So now Mary is
generating that project brief. And once
it is generated, we can uh go back into
Archon and see that. So we'll have to
wait a little bit because it's usually a
pretty long document. So, I'm going to
give it some time. So, all right, we
have our brief created from our analyst.
So, I'm going to actually go back.
Sorry, I'm jumping around a little bit
here. I'm going to go back in. Let's
take a look at this brief really quickly
that we've created. Plus one for
Dynamus, not just because of Cole, but
everyone in the community. I appreciate
that, Sean. Appreciate that a lot. Enjoy
Dynamus as well. Thank you. What is
happening in the community is really
crazy. Thank you, Toby. I appreciate it,
guys. Yeah, I I just like I have to call
out Dynamus a couple of times throughout
this stream because it is where a lot of
big things are happening. Um even like
with Archon and everything else around
building agents and context engineering,
but yeah. Okay, so here we go. We got
our document created. It's untitled
probably just because um Mary didn't
really understand exactly how to create
the document in Archon. I mean, it's
just, you know, the little things that
we're working through still. But here we
go. We got next steps. We've got a risk
assessment. And so again like all the
like genius things that the guy behind
BMAD uh created like all the research
he's done around prompting and project
management providing the right context
like we see that in the different
sections that we have here. We've got
our objective goal uh we got our project
overview the scope requirements
and uh if I scroll down a bit more I'm
curious if I can get to the things where
it's like more specific to the research
I did with claude code. Uh, okay. So,
technical specifications. Let's see if
this gets into it more. Uh, okay. We got
our tech stack. This looks pretty good.
Real time with sockets. Next.js.
Um, nice. Looks good.
Um,
okay. Direct SDK integration using
TypeScript Python wrappers. I don't
actually like that. I don't want Python
wrappers. So that's another thing I'll
say in general with context engineering
is like it's so important to validate
the output that you have uh from these
kinds of um sub aents just any coding
assistant in general they they'll
hallucinate weird things like this and
so I'm actually going to go back into
our analyst here and I'll say I don't
want a Python wrapper for anything.
Also, I need you to write out some more
pseudo code.
Uh,
do some more research on integrating
Cloud Code
SDK with a Nex.js backend. Search the
Cloud Code docs some more for this.
Okay. So, I'm going to have it correct
itself in a couple of ways here. So you
guys are seeing live how I'm like
looking through something finding those
those code smells or like the doc
smells. I'm like that is bad. Like I I
if I'm using Nex.js, it can be my front
end and my back end. I don't need Python
wrappers for anything. So clearly it got
confused just as it was searching
through the docs. But that's okay. So
yeah, it's going through and it's it's
performing rag and searching through the
code examples again. So we'll see what
kind of token or what kind of output
we're getting here. U okay. Th this is
actually what I wanted because now the
main thing that I needed to understand
is this import right here is actually
super crucial because we need to
leverage this query in order to call
into cloud code from our Nex.js backend
and I'll show you guys specifically the
docs
that it is referencing
is uh I'm talking about this or not
where is it this thing right here. So
import query from cloud code and then
like here's like a super basic example
of how you can call cloud code within
your TypeScript code. So like this would
be within our API endpoint in Nex.js. So
like this is what it just found when it
searched through using the knowledge
that we have crawled with archon. So
that's really good. That's exactly what
we wanted it to find. So now we can use
that and it's just wrapping up here. So
I'll let it wrap up. And it it also did
a web search here just to like
supplement his information, which by the
way, Archon doesn't have to fully
replace the web search that most coding
assistants have. Like you can use these
things together. Like I I love seeing it
when it performs some queries like
looking at code examples and performing
rag. And then it also does a web search
and it combines all that together. Um so
yeah, we'll see that. And then it's
going to update the archon project. So
it'll go ahead and update the brief that
we have in the UI as well. Uh did you
update the brief in Archon? make sure
you do so. Okay, because I need I need
to see that like I don't just want the
output here. I needed to update the
brief. And this is a a good example
where um okay, this sucks. I'll come to
this in a second. This is a good example
where um there's definitely an
opportunity to customize the prompting
and the global rules to make Archon
integrate more closely with BMAD. Like
the analyst here, Mary, she didn't quite
understand that like, oh, I have to go
back in and update Archon. I mean, she
apparently she said she did, but she
didn't, which is super weird. Like, that
seems like a problem in the prompting
somewhere. But like, yeah, there's
definitely an opportunity to have like a
like BMAD specific set of prompts where
it's like for the analyst, this is how
you work with Archon. For the PM, this
is how you work with Archon. Like,
that's kind of going back to what Maxim
said earlier. Like that's the goal that
one of the goals I have for Archon is
making it so that like there's a
preconfigured setup to work with these
different strategies. We have now
updated our brief. So, we did a bunch of
searching here. Now we've updated our
brief in Archon with some more technical
implementation. So let's actually go
back into Archon. Let's check this out.
So I'm going to refresh.
Go into docs. Oh, this is the wrong
project. Here we go. All right, we got a
title now, by the way. That's good. So
she Mary fixed things with version 1.1
to actually add a title. And cool. She
even labeled herself. This is cool. So
this is this is another neat
integration. Something that that another
big thing. I know that I'm talking a lot
about like the vision of Archon here um
as well as showing it, but I think
that's important. Another big thing we
want to do in Archon is make it
integrate really really deeply with the
idea of sub agents. And so different
documents can be labeled by the agent
that created them. Different tasks can
be assigned to different agents like we
can have Mary tasked with the um the
research and the like initial like kind
of like all the analyst stuff, right?
like we're creating our uh brief here
and then have like the project manager
tasked with the things that we have
related to creating the PRD having the
developer tasked with things related to
the coding and the QA agent like we can
have these different tasks that are
assigned to different things that we
have in our task list here and then have
them all coordinate together and so we
have like clear boundaries and what sub
aents are implementing what things based
on their assignment in archon that's
another thing that we're looking to do
as well so here's Mary has added version
1.1 for the brief. So we have a lot of
the same things as before like our scope
requirements and our text stack and
resource requirements but then we should
also have more of a technical
implementation.
Um like here for example we got some
actual like code in here and I don't I'm
not going to like go through and like
validate all this right now because I I
do want to move forward but like we have
some more like technical pieces to our
implementation now. Um so I think that's
a good starting point. we'll kind of go
with that. Um like talking about the
context manager pattern like things that
are specific from the clown code docs
that I found. So that's really good that
we have that now and we used archon to
fetch those things because who knows if
a web search would have been able to get
something that specific and um also it's
just nice that like we can pull code
examples and things from archon as well.
So okay, there we go. We'll go ahead and
um
move on to the next thing here. So we
have our brief created now. And so
actually what the founder of BMAD
recommends doing is clearing the
conversation entirely when we go on to
the next agent. So we've been working
with the analyst agent this entire time.
Now it is time to move on to the project
manager. So I do PM uh / PM and then
tab. So I'm now invoking the project
manager because essentially what we want
to do now is we want to take the brief
that we've created in Archon based on
all the research we've done and
everything and we want to turn it into a
PRD. So, it's going to be more
specifically like let's dive into the
specs for what we want to have created.
So, now we have John, our project
manager.
It's actually pretty cool because I
invoke John and right away he goes into
the existing project that we have for
Archon. That's pretty cool. So, we have
uh no tasks yet, but yeah, that's right.
Like right now, we just have the doc in
the project. So, I can do star help to
see what we can do with our project
manager. Now, the thing that I want to
do is create a PRD.
Um, so yeah, let's go ahead and I'm
going to copy the command here. So,
specifically what we want to do is we
want to create a PRD. And I I promised
that I would talk about working with
brownfield projects as well. So, we're
creating something from scratch here.
But if you're working in an existing
codebase, like I said, the big
difference is with existing code bases,
generally you're going to be more
referencing existing code versus with a
new project, you're looking to external
documentation for things like
architecture and best practices. And so
there are actually different commands
that we invoke in John, our project
manager in BMAD, based on if it's a new
project, this is for a new project, this
is for an existing project. like if
we're creating a PRD to add a new
feature into an existing codebase and so
I won't showcase this right now but yeah
the diagrams that we have for BMAD if I
go back to that here there is a
different step that we take based on if
it is a new project or an existing one
we're kind of at this stage in our
diagram now so I'm going to paste in my
command here uh whoops I did not mean to
do that let me copy the other thing that
I have uh just from my notes here my
other monitor okay this is what I meant
to do So we're going to call the create
PRD command and I'm telling it to pull
the brief that I have in the archon
project and then I want it to create the
PRD in archon as well. So we'll have a
second document after we invoke this
command. And also the big risk that I
have to tell you guys with claude in
general and with BMAD is it oftentimes
loves to overengineer.
And I'll show you guys what it looked
like. This this is really unfortunate.
the other example that I showed you
guys. So like this project that I had
created to like play around with BMAD
initially, it created 123 to-dos. It
completely overengineered with like
super random tasks and things like this
is the risk that you have when you have
Mary and John working together to create
your initial PRD. like things just get
so overly complex because it's trying to
build like this full productionready
software for you and you don't need that
to get started. It's way too much to to
go through in in one time at one time.
So yeah, I would say like my biggest tip
is in your global rules for your coding
assistant and just generally in your
prompting. It's important to be clear
quite often that you want things to be
simple because Claude loves to
overengineer. It's so annoying. You we
don't want 123 tasks. We want like 10 to
20. Like that's what I'm hoping to
create here. And so I'm telling it to
not overengineer and just keep things
simple. And so first we'll see it call
into archon. So it'll use the MCP to
grab the brief. U there we go. So we
pulled the brief. I can do control R to
expand it. We can see it. It pulled the
brief here. And then it's going to uh do
some research. I I forget exactly what
the project manager does to like create
the um to create the PRD. like I forget
if it does research or if it more just
like takes this and transforms it into a
a PRD like just with its own reasoning,
but we'll see in a second. This will
obviously go for a little bit though
because um or no, I guess it wait I
guess it's almost done. Here's our
simple PRD. Okay, product vision core
problem. Here's our solution. A
lightweight Nex.js app that wraps cloud
code SDK to enable multi-instance
management. This that's perfect. That is
a oneliner for exactly what I want to
create here. So it's good. it
understands what I'm looking for. And
then here's our MVP. Here are things
that are out of scope. So it's avoiding
complexity. I actually love this a lot.
So when I was playing with BMAD
initially, it was like including like
all of these things. Like I actually
remember seeing this explicitly that it
was like trying to implement like team
features so we could have multiple
people managing this this whole like
application which that's cool, but like
let's not try to implement that right
now. It's good that we're excluding some
of these things. So we're starting with
a simple local app like we have with
Archon. Then we can build these things
after which by the way that is actually
what we're doing for archon like in
scope what we built for the beta of
archon is let's give a simple and
beautiful user interface to manage
projects knowledge and documents. Then
when we start to move out of beta and
get a lot of feedback for how we can
improve the platform, then we'll start
to add in different context engineering
strategies and being able to manage the
full suite of context and let's get into
enterprise f features and make it so you
can host archon like that. Those are all
the things that are coming for archon.
But we not we got to start simple
because if you try to do too much at
once like coding assistants like to do,
you are just in for a world of hurt. And
so we're starting simple. I I actually
appreciate this a lot. So, let me go
back down.
Okay, so uh yeah, out of scope. Here's
our simple architecture.
I mean, I kind of wish it expanded on
this a little bit more at least, but
that's okay because I actually love it
when coding assistants will output like
the code base, like the structure that
they're they're looking to implement.
But yeah, here is our text stack. Xterm
for terminal display sounds good to me.
NextJS14 Tailwind looks good. Um, no
need for Okay, so it's just going to do
local storage for the config. So, we're
not even using a database, which I think
that's fine, I guess, for this
implementation, we'll call it good. U
maybe it's actually a little too simple,
but I think for the cases of our live
stream here, because we're already at
one and a half hours, this is probably
this is probably good.
So, yeah. All right. Um, let me go to
success criteria, development
principles. Good. Good. User journey.
Okay. Now, now we create this document
in uh Archcom. So, cool. All right. So,
let's actually take a look and make sure
this was created, that it's looking
good. So, I'll go to my projects. I'll
go to this one that we have new here. Go
to docs. And there we go. Here is our
PRD. Nice. Cloud code instance manager
simplified PRD.
And um yeah, looks like there's a couple
of little issues here. Like I said, the
docs part of Archon is like the most
experimental right now. And so, it's
expected to not like look the perfect
right now. There actually is a PR out
from Sean to improve a lot of these
things. So, we got we got improvements
coming for this like really really soon.
Um but yeah, um this is looking really
good though. We got our text stack
folder structure. Here's our scope
looking really good. Like perfect. All
right, we got our PRD. Like now we're
ready to dive into the implementation.
Um yeah, like this is this is great. I
love how it looks overall even though
it's not like perfect yet. And then
there's also a markdown editor. If you
want to edit things yourself, you can do
so. So you can be a part of the process
of editing the doc right in archon and
then saving it to your superbase. So
like all these documents are stored in
superbase so you can reference them
between sessions even between users very
easily. Like one thing that us like core
maintainers for archon like everyone in
the dynamis community what we're looking
to do is actually like spin up a shared
archon instance which it doesn't
actually mean like here here's the cool
thing with archon. If you guys want to
share your Archon instance with other
people because everything is stored in
Superbase, it's not like you have to
host one Archon instance and then deploy
it to the cloud. Like you can have
everyone running their own Archon
instances locally just pointing to the
same Superbase database that you have in
the cloud. And so obviously that
wouldn't work for like localhosted
superbase. But if you're going to like
superbase.com and creating a project
there, then everyone can can use the
same archon instance. You can have
everyone working on the same projects
and docs. They're just all running their
own archon pointing to the super basease
in the cloud. It's pretty cool. So I'm
going to I'm going to clear and I'm
going to go on to the next agent here.
So going to our flow within BMAD.
Let's go back. So, next up, we have our
architect. So, we're going to create uh
the architecture from the PRD. And also,
I'm going to actually have the architect
create tasks for us in Archon. So, I'll
do slash architect.
Good. Good. And then I'll do the help
command after it runs its little intro
message for me here.
Um or I guess it's going right away.
Wait, what is it doing? I'll help you
set up the Archon project management
system for a BMAD app. Let me start by
checking what's available in the Archon
MCP and create a project structure. Um,
all right. It's just going right away.
This is interesting. I'm just going to
let it run. Like I said, we're
freestyling today. When I tested the
architect before, it didn't do this, but
now it's just like running right away.
Um, and it's okay. So, now now we're
integrating BMAD with PRP. Let's go.
Okay, this is interesting. I'm I'm just
going to see what it does. Um, what is
it doing?
Okay, I need to stop it now. Sorry.
Sorry. Sorry. Uh, architect. What's the
architect's name? The architect didn't
even tell me what its name is. It just
went right into it. Uh, what is your
name? All right, cuz it create the the
thing that I made me have to stop it is
that it created a third project and
that's that's not good. Like I needed to
I'm going to just go ahead and delete
this project because I need it to
reference the existing one because we
got our docs here. So, but that's all
good. Like it's fine just to correct it
quick. Okay. So, it's Winston. So,
Winston dove in right away before even
introducing himself to me. Okay. Okay.
Winston, I need you to use the existing
project in Archon and then I'll just
call out the name.
Uh, so let me go back here. I'll copy
this because I I just don't want to
reference the old one that I had just to
like show you guys a previous attempt.
So, um, yeah. Okay. So using this
project read the PRD that we have stored
in that project in archon.
Then I want you to shard the PRD into
tasks
uh no more than 20 tasks and put those
in the tasks for the archon project. All
right. So basically what I'm telling it
to do is pull down this document right
here. And then based on all the
requirements that we have and
everything, I want it to just create 20
tasks. So we start building up our
cananban board here. So we can dive into
the implementation. And so I don't know
if 20 is enough or not. I just want to
like really keep it simple here. And so
yeah, so it's pulling the document here.
And now we're starting to create some
tasks. And so we should be able to see
this pop up in real time as we go. So
let's see what it's doing here. Here,
I'm going to go ahead and refresh.
Um, okay, there we go. All right, so
it's creating some tasks
there. I got to Sorry, I'm having an
issue with my browser here.
Um, okay. Yeah, there we go. So, it's
creating some tasks here. Like, let's
see this one right here. Create cloud
SDK wrapper class with TypeScript. Looks
good. And it's referencing the specific
file to implement. It's talking about
error handling with some like specific
errors that so like this class the CLI
not found error like it found this from
the cloud code documentation. So this is
based on its research that it did with
the archon a rag the functionality that
we gave it. So yeah it's looking good.
So it's going through it's creating all
these tasks here and um yeah I'll just
kind of let it run with that. So I'll go
to the chat here while we got the the
tasks being created in archon.
Um, Winston is defin on the chopping
block. Yeah, come on, Winston. No, it's
all good. Um, because like I said,
there's probably a lot of opportunities
to integrate BMAD with Archon a lot more
with like just even the way we're
setting up the global rules, telling
Winston how to use Archon, so it doesn't
make those assumptions like he did in in
um initially, which yeah, so I don't
really blame him, but it was funny. So,
yeah, LLMs and and sub agents, they're
they're inconsistent in the way that
they leverage the tools that we give
them. And so, that's why it's really
important to be super specific with our
prompts. Let's go back to um I'll just
refresh to make sure. Oh, no, it was
already loaded here. So, we got the 20
tasks for our project here. So, it's
starting all the way at the beginning
with initialize next.js 14 with
TypeScript and Tailwind.
Um and then we get create API routes.
um for different things. Looks good.
Build, create the instance model form.
Okay. All right. Good. Good. All the way
to final testing and GitHub release
preparation, which maybe that's a little
bit of overengineering, but yeah, within
each of these tasks, we also have a
description. So, we're giving more
context to whatever ends up implementing
this, what exactly we're looking for.
And here we're specifying things like
using externs. So, it's very much
referencing the plan that we have in our
PRD. It's putting those things into the
descriptions here. like we have our text
stack being referenced throughout our
tasks. And so everything is like very
integrated here. That's the beauty of
it. And so now going back to my um
architect here, there's a lot of other
things we can do. So, I'll kind of like
continue with the common theme here of
like I'm not going to be using
everything within these sub aents just
to keep things concise, but I want to
like show you guys some of the other
things you can do with these different
sub aents with the BMAD method and
probably some other things that could
like integrate more with Archon as well.
So, our Winston
is a devious little architect that
didn't even introduce himself at first.
He can do a lot of other things. We can
um do some more research if we wanted
to. Like I could actually have him like
research best practices for
architecture. Going back to Archon for
the docs, we can have him create a
front-end architecture specifically,
which if I had the time here, I probably
would actually do this. I think that
would make sense because a lot of what
I'm building here is relying on the
front end being quite robust, especially
being able to like have terminal output
for our different cloud code instances.
Like definitely that would be important.
Um, however, to keep things concise, I'm
going to clear. I'm going to say we're
good here. So we got our tasks, we've
got our PRD, like we have all the
context we need to really start diving
into the implementation. So our PRD plus
our tasks plus probably leveraging our
knowledge base even more. Like that's
everything that our development agent
now needs. And so there are some
different agents within BMAD. Like we
have the dev agent. I could dive into
using this. Uh we also have the
um scrum master agent. If I wanted to
invoke the scrum master agent, we could
dive into these things. That's really
going to be that second part of the flow
that we have in BMAD. So like we
basically went through this whole
planning workflow and I know I skipped a
lot of things, but like we went through
it and a lot of it is optional. And now
we've gotten to the point we're ready to
go to the development workflow. And so
we kind of go in a cycle here where we
generate these stories based on our PRD.
I kind of did something a little bit
differently in Archon where instead of
stories, I more just have like the
different tasks in our project. And so
now we can start knocking these off one
by one.
And in order to do this, I actually kind
of want to use PRP.
Like I said, freestyling. I'm going to
switch from BMAD to PRP. So we used BMAD
for the planning. And that's kind of
equivalent to creating like our initial
MD file where we're just describing
those initial requirements that we have
to create our PRP. And so I'm going to
do something kind of interesting here.
So within my uh VS Code, I'll I'll just
pop this up quick. Within my VS Code,
the same place that I have BMAD set up,
I also downloaded the um the starter for
PRP. So we have our two commands to
execute and generate PRPS. I've got my
template to base a PRP off of. By the
way, this is all available to you guys
in the context engineering intro
repository that I've covered on my
channel a couple of times. And so I'm
just pulling all of the like getting
started stuff from this repository so we
can implement PRP because what I'm going
to do is I'm going to take the spec the
PRD that we generated with BMAD and I'm
going to turn that into a PRP so we can
just start implementing it with all the
tasks that we have in Archon as well.
So, this might be a little bit of
overengineering, but I think this is
cool to experiment with. So, we're just
going to do it. We're going to go ahead
and do it. So, I'm going to do
slashgenerate PRP. And then, typically
with PRPS, you want to reference a file
that has your initial requirements, but
instead, I'm going to say uh look at the
or I'm going to say use the PRD we have
in the Archon project. And then I'm
going to go back to Archon because I got
to copy that name again of the project
here. Cloud code instance manager Nex.js
control center. There we go. So copy
this, paste it. There we go. Okay. So
we're going to generate a PRP which is
going to it's going to take the PRD and
turn it more into a prompt for our
coding assistant. So we have things like
validation gates so it understands how
to validate its work. We're going to be
more explicit with like the final
codebase architecture that we want. And
so yeah, I'm gonna I'm gonna let it run
and do that. Um, so yeah, let's actually
go back in the terminal here because we
have our PRP. I'm gonna get get back to
the the coding for a bit, but I really
appreciate being in the chat with you
guys. Um, so like I said, like we're
we're going through this thing. I don't
think we're going to build it from like
fully build it here. Um, because the
focus is showing you how to integrate
BMAD with Archon and now we're talking
about PRP as well. We're freestyling and
I just want to talk with you guys, have
a chat with you guys and and answer your
questions. So I'm putting a lot of
emphasis into that as well. But yeah,
here is our PRP.
So, I'm going to open a preview of it so
we can take a look.
Uh, there we go. At our purpose, our
core principles, and our goal. So, we're
following the base PRP. This is the
template that we're basing this off of.
Um, let me go back. There we go. So, we
got our why. We got our what, what we're
building here. We got our success
criteria. Here's all the documentation
that we want it to uh read through,
which that's good. But also, I want to
tell it to use Archon as well. So, I'll
say use Archon for Claude Code SDK and
Nex.js Docs.
Um, yeah. So, I'll just I think I'll
just leave it there. That's good. So,
within the documentation and reference,
I didn't really I should have been
explicit in creating the PRP that I
wanted to use Archon, but this is going
to work as well. So, I'll just add it
here. must read. You must use Archon for
cloud code SDK and Nex.js doc so we can
kind of more supplement the research
that we've already did with the Archon
MCP and then doing some research on like
Xterm and and real-time patterns. Looks
good. Here's our desired codebase. See
this this is beautiful. Like this is
what I like seeing. And Claude actually
does a really good job at respecting the
desired codebase tree. And so this is
what our end result is going to look
like where we have um we have our API
where we have the routes for managing
cloud code instances. We have the
different components for displaying the
terminal and the logs. Like this is
really good. We've got known gotas and
then we have a lot of pseudo code here
and the list of tasks that need to be
implemented here which I'm going to just
tell it to use archon. So maybe there's
a little bit of a disconnect here. Um
but yeah, it looks pretty close to what
we actually had in in um Archon. So I
might have even referenced it. I'm not
totally sure exactly but yeah then we
just have a lot of pseudo code. So yeah
and then uh yeah I guess the very last
thing is the validation gates or
validation loops. So one of the really
important parts of the PRP framework is
telling the coding assistant how it can
iterate and validate its own output. So
like with linting checks and we're going
to have it write unit tests and
integration tests. Uh which I'm actually
going to take out integration tests
because that's probably too much for
right now. So I'm going to go ahead and
take this out. So again, just like with
out with validating code that's outputed
from your coding assistant, you want to
validate the PRP before you execute it.
Make sure that it's aligned with what
you want to create and that it's not
overengineering because that's another
big thing that coding assistants do.
Like I was talking about earlier, we got
our final validation checklist and then
some anti-atterns here. So we're looking
good. And our confidence score
is not as high as I want it to be, but
just for the sake of brevity, I'm going
to go ahead and kick this off. So, I'm
going to clear the conversation,
and I'm going to say execute PRP. And
then the path to our PRP is PRP's claude
code instance
manager MD. And then, uh, the other
thing is I'm going to kick this off. I'm
going to say use the archon project for
task management and archon for rag. Um,
and then I'll say the project is and
then I'll go back into
here. I got to I keep I should just like
memorize this. Let me copy this. Cool.
Go back in here and paste that. All
right. There we go. Okay. And it
actually was checking for projects
already. So it it knew to use archon,
but now I'm just being explicit telling
it which project to use. So there we So
now now it's it knows which project to
use, but it's going to look there
already anyway. So all right, we're
using Archon right away for our
implementation. So we got one task
that's done. Okay, now it moved on to
the next one is in progress. So now it's
installing configuring cloud code with
Xterm. Okay, so we're good. So it's
moving through the implementation. Now
the rest of this we're just going to
have to wait a while because it's going
to have to knock through all these
tasks. But you can very much see that
it's doing so and it's leveraging Archon
and this is beautiful. I want to ask
again, wouldn't it be better idea to
have ready-made boiler plates to start
with and have the agent choose the best
one that fulfills most requirements and
build on that? Yes, definitely. And um
yeah, that's one of the things that I
was talking about earlier for one of my
long-term visions for Archon. So, I I
love talking about the long term for
Archon because as exciting as it is what
we have built right now, there's so many
more things we have to make it like way
better. And so, let me talk about that
again. And this might be like a little
bit of reiterating, but still it's it's
it's really cool to talk about and just
like get our brain juices flowing for
what's what's possible with a tool like
Archon. So, one of the things that we
have in the Dynamis community
is, and I've kind of been referencing
this, but I haven't been showing it yet.
We have the context engineering hub. So,
this is private to the Dynamus
community, but I definitely want to like
share a lot of these resources um with
all of like just to my YouTube channel
as well.
But one thing we're working on in
Dynamis together
is we're working on the context
engineering hub. This is going to be
basically a a gold mine of resources for
PRP templates and slash commands and
global rules and cloud hooks and sub
aents that everyone is contributing
together as a community. We started this
like really recently actually.
And so the goal with one of the goals
with this is to eventually integrate it
with archon
where archon can look at this context
engineering hub and it can say you would
tell it like I want to build a nex.js JS
application or I want to build a
pideantic AI agent and archon will
search through these different things
just like it searches through knowledge
with rag and it'll be like oh sweet here
is the pyantic AI PRP template so you
have a boilerplate like you said Ramy
and like oh here are some slash commands
uh in uh cloud hooks and sub aents that
will work well to help you build out
this agent and then oh here's the Python
global rules like if we go to our global
rules here and we're continue like we
just started building this out so
there's not a ton here yet, but we're
working on a lot of resources here. Like
here, here's Raasmus' global rules that
he uses for all Python applications. And
so Archon would pull this because you're
building a Python Pantic AI agent and
then it would go into your knowledge and
be like, "Oh, you're building with
Pyantic AI, so let me go ahead and and
find the what I want to crawl for Pantic
AI." And then I'll go ahead and crawl
that and add that and then I'll make a
new project for you in Archon. So you
have like all this boiler plate set up
for you to just like And by the way,
look at how much it implemented already.
We're already on task eight out of 20,
which is pretty sweet. But yeah, anyway,
like that that's like the the dream for
Archon to make it so that it is the
command center for all context
engineering, just getting you started no
matter the project that you have. And a
lot of that does rely on us building out
this context engineering hub. But this
and Archon are like the two big things
that we have going on in Dynamis. U
maybe that like and the AI agent mastery
course where I show how to build agents
from start to finish. So, like I said, a
lot of really exciting things going on
in the community. So, if this sounds
interesting to you, like if you want to
dive in and contribute and even just
leverage these resources and be a part
of the long-term vision for Archon,
dynamis.ai, that's the place to check
out. So, I'm going to plug it again
because it just relates so much to what
we're talking about here. Um, and
everything that we got going on. So,
yeah, let me go back and see where we
are at with Claude Code.
Okay, so yeah, it's just chugging away
like it's it's killing it. Nice job,
Cloud Code. So, yeah. Okay. Um, our
application is Wait, is it actually
ready? Okay, I'm going to try this. I I
doubt it's going to work first try
because I cut a lot of corners to just
like speed up things and show you guys
the whole BMAD, but let's try this out
actually. This would be so cool if we at
least get some kind of visual here.
Uh, let me make sure npm install. Let me
make sure everything's installed first
and then I'll try to run it. Okay. npm
rundev.
Um, okay.
No errors. Oh, that'd be so cool. All
right. Let me let me spin this up.
Uh, okay. So, it looks really bad.
It looks so bad. I guess maybe there's
an there must there's probably a
tailwind issue.
Yeah, there's a tailwind issue. Okay.
So, so the the uh CSS isn't working.
It's probably a simple thing, but
help me help me make a million dollars.
Create instance.
Okay, that's actually really cool. Um,
okay, so we got another error. Okay, so
we got a couple of errors, but like
clearly it's like kind of there. Um,
there's two things we'd have to fix.
Okay, let's try to fix I'm actually
let's try to fix these. So, I'm going to
go back to my claw code and say I'm
getting this error for Tailwind CSS.
And then also uh when I start a claude
instance, I get this error and it is
stuck on what is it stuck on right now.
So I'm just trying to be like kind of
specific here. Usually when you're
troubleshooting things with coding
assistance, it's helpful to be like
quite specific on like when the error is
happening, what the error is. So it's
stuck on processing prompt this error.
I'm just typing this off camera really
quick. So I'm going to copy this. Uh if
I go to the issues that we're getting,
uh there we go. If I look at the I
forget how to Oh, yeah. Here we go. Um,
I'll just copy the full call stack here.
Okay, there we go. So, I'm sending it
in. I accidentally pasted the call stack
twice, but it's probably fine. But,
yeah, let's just have it lock out these
things and we'll see what we can get.
So, I'll just be ready to run it again
here. But, okay, that'd be so I mean, we
got like kind of something. and it looks
terrible, but um I there's no way I
would expect to oneshot this application
even if I spent a lot of time
architecting and validating the PRP,
which especially because I didn't like I
definitely wasn't expecting it to be
great out the gate, but I I feel like
just just with like my intuition and
experience with coding assistance and
what I was looking at there, I don't and
like how specific the errors were, I
don't think we're that far from at least
having something pretty cool. Um, okay.
I'm gonna try something right now. I'm
gonna try running the server even though
it's in the middle of stuff, just
because maybe it's to the point now
where it's working. Um, oh,
okay. It is. It's kind of It's getting
there. This is cool. Okay, now we got a
real UI. So, we fixed the we fixed the
stupid Tailwind stuff for the most part.
Um Oh, yeah. So, it's just running the
the type checks at the end here. So, I
think it is pretty much done. Okay.
Well,
yeah, 24-hour stream. Definitely not a
24-hour stream. Um, if you guys uh if
you guys look on my live tab on my
channel, I do have a 12-h hour stream
from before I really started diving into
YouTube. Um, I'll just leave that there
and move on. But yeah. Okay. So, create
a new instance. Code review assistant.
Help me make a million dollars. All
right. Create instance.
Okay.
I don't see any logs
and Okay. So 2% right before the auto
compact we finished and it's um view
terminal. Okay. So it doesn't look like
it's working.
So okay. So I don't know. I don't know
if we're 80% of the way there. Like I
said, it's the expectation that
especially cuz I rush through some of
the things that it's not going to be
like perfect perfect, but like we've got
something to start with and Vive coding
is never going to get you 100% of the
way there. And we definitely did like
Archon helps with structured approach,
context engineering, but what we did
today rushing through things was more
vibe coding than I'd want to do
definitely. Um, but like I hope that
like I explain things well enough like
when you'd want to dive in deeper so
that you understand how to not vibe code
as well. So it's like let's go through
things quick, but I'll speak to like
when you'd want to slow down. I hope
that makes sense. And so we definitely
could be making this a lot better if we
put more time into it. But yeah, I mean
it's it's we've got something working
here. All right. So yeah, I think I'm
going to go ahead and wrap up the stream
now. I've been talking for three hours
straight and I think I'm going to take
uh most of the day off and and get that
recap uploaded tomorrow. And uh I'll um
I'm going to be super active in Dynamis
tomorrow as well and then going into
next week. Well, I mean, I always am,
but uh yeah, I know that I already heard
from my wife that there's influx of
people joining Dynamis, which I
appreciate a lot, guys, because we're
going to be doing some amazing things
together. So, yeah. All right. Um I'm
going to eat some lunch, too. Right.
Yeah. I have not been drinking any
water. I have I have my water here
specifically so I could drink,
but I I never remember to do that while
I'm in a live stream. I always forget.
There was one live stream uh a couple
ago that I did. I actually gave myself
co like I brought coffee to the live
stream and I remember holding it up at
the start of the of the live stream. I'm
like here's my NHN mug. I got coffee cuz
we got a a a chill casual live stream
today and I'm going to be sipping my
coffee and then I sipped it once the
entire live stream cuz I totally forgot
about it because I get so into it. Like
you guys have no idea how much it takes
like mental effort to be like watching
the chat, watching my stream and like
kind of checking on viewership and then
like diving into Claude Code or whatever
and and like it's a lot but it's really
fun. Like it's so worth it. So yeah,
thank you everyone for being here and
being a part of Archon. Um as you can
see like not perfect right now, but it's
freaking awesome and there's so much
more that we got coming really soon for
it and a really amazing long-term
vision. So yeah, definitely check out
Dynamus if you guys want to be a really
big part of it. Um, but also like it's
totally public open source project and
we got a public community as well. So
yeah, options either way for you guys.
But yeah, big things coming for Archon
short and long term. So thank you
everyone for being here and following
along and your questions and comments.
Hope that you guys have a great rest of
your weekend. And with that, I will see
you guys in the next